birds of the air that come to pick the
word that lands without understanding
have no place in this meeting. I release
a hearing ear and a sing eye and I
declare that understanding shall be your
portion in the mighty name of Jesus. The
Bible says as Peter was yet still
speaking the Holy Ghost fell upon them.
I declare by the release of your word
may people encounter truth before they
even come to a place of encountering
power. Lord, I take away every heaviness
in the atmosphere and I declare may you
speak to your children as a father will
speak to his own. Take charge of my
mouth. I don't lean on my understanding
but I rely on you Holy Spirit. And it is
in Jesus name. And the church say
amen. We can have our seats.
Let's appreciate the worshippers.
I have um I want to appreciate all of
you for making it for this service. I
want to appreciate uh the amazing online
family uh that uh follow us globally. Um
I I was doing some prayers with a team
in Europe called the Gideonss who always
gather and they they are part of this
mandate. There's also a team that
gathers in Boston and uh there's a team
that also gathers in the UK and we bless
the Lord for giving us the privilege. I
was surprised when someone sent me a
message all the way from China and I
said my God uh we need to be faithful
with his assignment. Hallelujah. And so
we give God all the glory. And even for
you who gather here physically every
Sunday without fail, we give God the
glory. We pray that we are going to be
faithful with the assignment. I want to
appreciate my wife uh for allowing me to
pursue this calling for the many years.
There's one day she looked at me and
told me I have released you to the
church. It takes an understanding woman
to do that. Let's appreciate uh mom
Claudia Wetto.
She has never stressed me. Sometimes I
always go to tell her that I'm traveling
and she will ask me today. meaning that
in her heart she knows uh you know this
guy is a missionary and God has called
him for the body that does not mean that
I don't give them their time. Amen.
And so we began by looking at
understanding family battles.
And today I know we are in talks looking
unto Jesus. And I felt in my spirit what
a day to discuss about this
and point our families to Jesus.
And last Sunday uh we checked on what we
call generational altars. I want to
request you to pay attention because we
say that we all come from families and
none of us has the power to choose which
family to be born from. Nobody chose the
family that they came from. So if there
are certain dealings in certain
bloodlines, it takes divine partnership
for there to be deliverance. Before I
even continue, the deliverance of
families is not external.
The deliverance of families is always
internal. It's an internal operation.
When the Lord wants to deliver a family,
he will look for a man in that family, a
person that will give the Holy Spirit
legality of operation.
So many family battles are not worn
externally, they are won internally.
The battles in my father's house cannot
be won by pastor Jimmy. Neither can I
win the battles in Pastor Jimmy's home.
But God can allow me to pray for him,
release grace upon his life so that he
can go and enter and enter into a
spiritual operation and begin the
assignment of operation. That is why
it's a very personal thing. We this is
not a matter where we rely on a powerful
pastor. It is good to have a powerful
pastor who can activate grace in your
life. But even a powerful pastor to some
extent may not be able to fully execute
the battles in your father's home.
That's why you must rise as a deliverer
and as a savior and also rise as a
person that the Lord can partner to
pioneer another bloodline.
When we come to family battles, we can
engage in three levels. Family battles,
you can engage in three levels. The
first level of engagement, you can
engage as a victim.
You can engage as a victim. What do I
mean? Let me give an example. Let's
assume you come from a family that is
being attacked by the spirit of
alcoholism
and it happens that you have also been
attacked by that spirit and you go and
receive Jesus in a rehab. So by the time
you are rising, you are rising as a
victim. Or let me give another example.
Let's assume you come from a family
where marriages don't work and now you
have already become a single mother or a
divorce because there is an Asian
pattern in your bloodline of divorce and
now you are raising children and they
already subjected to the pattern and by
the grace of God you hear this message
and you begin to wage war and say mine
may have failed but for these children
because I failed it does not mean they
will fail. Is someone getting me? So
there is a level where we contend
from a place of we are already victims
of certain uh patterns and certain
battles in family. There is another
level uh which I call it I try to typify
it as the freedom fighter. So, so there
is a level that I call the freedom
fighter level.
That level means you will fight the
battle, but you may not see the results
in your day.
But generations that come will benefit
from your prayers, from your fastings,
from your declarations. So you might die
without seeing results.
In this nation, we have people that are
called the founding fathers.
I don't even know a name of any ma ma.
But today, I enjoy a free Kenya because
men that I didn't know fought the
battle.
Today, we have the freedom of our
constitution. We have the freedom as a
nation because of men who fought the
battle. If you ask your neighbor to name
10 Ma Mau veterans, they don't know,
but they are enjoying the freedom of
those veterans, someone paid the price.
Are we together? And and some of us, we
may not see the results in our time, but
the seeds we are planting will speak for
generations. Tell that neighbor, don't
get tired.
In heaven, there is no wastage. Are we
together? And number three, there are
people who deliver their homes by
revelation.
By revelation. So you didn't become a
victim.
Neither did you fight without seeing the
results. But revelation comes upon you
right now. Maybe you are a couple and
you're married and you took time to
study your bloodline and you discovered
by the way your grandfather was
divorced. You come from a broken home. I
also come from a broken home. So this
spirit if we are not sensitive it will
pursue us. And by revelation you begin
to pray and you begin to contend because
you already know there is a certain
pattern trying to pursue you and that
pattern is in your bloodline.
There are some levels of battles and
some levels of forgiveness and some
levels of engagement. And let me speak
to the couples. There is a level of
conflict that is beyond he did she did.
It is a spirit trying to implement
ancient patterns.
Lord, give me the grace.
I met a man, a friend of ours, and we
were just having a boy talk, laughing,
and he said, and I repeat his words. He
said,
And he said, "It's not that my wife has
anything. My wife is the best." And then
we asked him,
"What is your background?" He said, "The
man I'm named after, my grandfather had
seven wives."
And I knew it is not Hakyamongu.
There is an Asian spirit of polygamy
that pursues men in that family. Am I
speaking to anyone? I am not here to
encourage infidelity in marriage, but
I'm here to also help us begin to
diagnose matters not with the eyes of
social complexity, but begin to see
deeply and understand the man I married
comes from a place of polygamy. Is it a
matter we need to agree as a couple? I
one of the sons in the house came and
told me pastor I come from a place of
polygamy and all my uncles that are
polygamous are successful but I am the
one fighting that thing. I said son
continue because by revelation he knows.
Is someone getting me?
You are married to a woman. Her
grandmother was a single mother. Her
mother is a single mother and that thing
keeps on pushing her. She has packed
seven times leaving you.
Am I becoming too real?
That backing and sometimes the thing you
have disagreed upon when you look at it
is an unissue. But every time you
disagree that Asian spirit begins to
tell her you can be independent. That is
the time you need to look at that wife
and tell her devil get behind me Satan
because I know this is not my wife
behaving. I know there is an Asian power
that wants to sponsor singlehood.
So three levels. Number one, you can you
can you can enter as a victim. Is
someone getting me? You can also enter
as a freedom fighter. You may not see
the results in your day, but God has
partnered with you to make sure that a
generation is safe. And number three,
you can also enter
as out of revelation that the Lord just
reveals to you. You don't need to be a
victim. But by that revelation, you
know, there is a there is a current
battle and understanding that I need to
operate with because if I live life by
social lenses, I will not win in some
spiritual battles.
And today I want to check on something
that is connected. They are
interconnected.
I want to check on what I call
generational patterns.
Generational patterns.
And because I'm I'm not in a hurry to
finish this matter,
where my time will come to an end is
where I will stop. Are we together?
Somebody say generational patterns.
For those who bought the book,
I have defined a pattern is a repeated
sequence.
A pattern is a repeated sequence.
For power to flow,
either spiritual or demonic,
it needs a pattern. For power to flow,
either spiritual or demonic, there has
to be a pattern.
By the time you're seeing these lights
lighting up, there is a whole engineer
that came and laid down cables in a
certain pattern. So that by one switch
there is a generator there. By one
switch all the lights go on and by that
one switch all the lights can go off.
So that when you switch on the light you
don't see currency flowing but you can
see the effect of that currency.
So there is a switch and the moment it's
on power begins to flow in that pattern
and when the pattern is complete things
will begin to manifest.
Let me have some four people here so
that I can demonstrate something.
So we have said power does not flow if
there is no pattern
and there must be a switch. So so it is
not the switch that produces the light
because a switch that is not connected
to a pattern cannot manifest anything.
So there is a level where I love these
guys. They are all dressed the same and
they're looking smart.
It's a pattern.
I I want to show you something because
one of the one of the people in
scripture that pioneered a generational
pattern is a man we call the father of
faith, Abraham.
There are almost six things or five
things that Abraham pioneered as a
pattern and we're going to look at them.
Number one, Abraham pioneered a pattern
of marrying beautiful women,
beautiful wives. It was a pattern. We
will look at it. Abraham married a
beautiful wife or a fair wife to a point
he was contending with kings.
Every territory he entered, he had to
lie because Sarah was beautiful.
That's the Bible.
Hallelujah.
Abraham pioneered a pattern of lies.
He lied to the king of Geral in Genesis
20. He lied to the king of Egypt that
Sarah is my wife.
Abraham also pioneered a pattern of
marrying barren women.
Sarah was barren.
Sarah was barren. So there was a
pattern. There was a pattern.
He also pioneered another pattern where
the firstborn misses the blessing.
The firstborn misses the blessing.
We all know that the firstborn of
Abraham according to the flesh was
Ishmael.
That was the first son that Abraham got.
The firstborn
in the spirit was Ishmael.
And when it came to giving blessing, the
Bible says that
um Ishmael
and Hagi were released
and they were given gifts. Later Abraham
marries
later in the book of Genesis. He marries
after Sarah and gets children and he
gave them gifts.
When it came to blessing, Isaac was the
second born and is the one who attracted
the blessing. So in that lineage, son's
firstborns missed their blessing.
He also pioneered a pattern of escaping
to Egypt.
Anytime there was a problem in the
promised land, he pioneered a pattern of
escaping to Egypt.
A pattern of escaping to Egypt. So this
is Abraham. How many things are in him?
Number one,
a pattern of marrying fair women, a
pattern of lies, a pattern of attracting
barren wives, a pattern of firstborn
missing the blessing, and a pattern of
escaping to Egypt. Now, let's go to
Isaac, the son.
Isaac marries Rebecca.
The day Isaac saw No. Is it Rebecca?
The day Isaac saw Rebecca, it was love
at first sight
because Abraham sent
his servant, the senior one, to go to
the house
and the lady that will serve him, that
that's the covenant he made. The lady
that will serve him, that will be the
lady. And when Isaac saw Rebecca coming,
Isaac fell in love and that was it. And
because of that, he also pursued the
pattern of his father. He also lied
just as his father.
And we begin some of the we'll begin to
see that some of these things became
worse in the next generation. Rebecca
was barren
to a point that Isaac needed to consult
God concerning the baronness of Rebecca.
When the children were born, Esau, who
is the firstborn,
missed the blessing and Jacob got the
blessing.
Is it making sense now?
Dro came.
He was almost escaping to Egypt. The
Lord intervened.
But there is a time Isaac entered Egypt
and lied about his wife Rebecca. Like
father, like son.
Let's come to the third generation.
I told you last Sunday there is always
the pattern of the dad. Many things
escalate in the that generation.
many things
escalating the third. So now we come to
the third generation.
Now we are moving from Abraham
Isaac. Let's look at the pattern of
Jacob.
Jacob attracts two barren wives.
Leia and Rachel. They are both barren.
Both of them need intervention for
delivery.
Re Jacob worked for 14 years to get a
beautiful wife.
It is in your Bible because the man
comes from a lineage where people marry
beautiful women. He does not know what
sponsors his effort to work for 14
years. Oh Jacob, there is an ancient
pattern in your family where people can
do anything even lie to marry a
beautiful wife.
Now we in the third generation
that Jacob perfected lies.
The father began with a simple lie. In
the that generation, Jacob lied to his
father Isaac. Jacob lied to Laban. Jacob
survived by lies.
Some of you already locating themselves.
Show mom and you're like, "Hey, I'm the
that generation."
Am I speaking to anyone?
And and when you look at this pattern,
when there was drought,
when Joseph entered Egypt,
Jacob not only went to Egypt, he dwelt
in Egypt and died in Egypt.
There was a pattern. Anytime there is
trouble, we go to Egypt.
In the days of Jacob, the man dwelt
in Egypt.
Let's look at Genesis 2020.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Okay. That's what I
was looking for. Genesis ch 20 and verse
2. Are you seeing the lie there? Look at
Genesis 21 and verse4. Let me just give
you some scriptures because the reason
why I'm not going to the scriptures is
so that I'm able to summarize this thing
in a way you can understand. Are we
together? Because when we begin out to
dig it in scripture, it might take us
another one year.
Can see what happened.
The man survived by lies. I'm saying
Genesis 21:14.
Genesis 21. So Abraham rose early in the
morning and took bread and skill of
water and put it on her shoulder. He
gave it and the boy to Hagger and sent
her away. Then she departed and wandered
in the wilderness. The son missed the
blessing. Now let's go to Jacob's hands.
The first son of Jacob was Reuben.
The first son of Jacob was Reuben. Look
at Genesis 49 from verse one and verse
two.
Beginning 1 2 3 because this one you
have to read. Reuben missed the
blessing. And what happened is that a
door of a cast now was open. Not only
did Reuben miss the blessing, but he was
cast. And Jacob called his sons and
said, "Gather together that I may tell
you what shall befall you in the last
days.
Gather together and hear you, oh sons of
Jacob, and listen to Israel, your
father. Reuben, you are my firstborn."
Everybody read, "Ruben, you are my
firstborn. my might and the beginning of
my strength. The excellency of dignity
and the excellency of power
and stable as water you shall not exile.
But because you went up to your father's
bed, what happened? Then you defiled it.
He went up to my couch. Look at it. Look
at five. Everybody read. H. No, no, no.
Look at four. Sorry. Sorry. Sorry.
Everybody read. and stable as water, you
shall not exhale because you went up to
your father's bed. Then you defiled it.
So this was a curse.
The man, the son was cast never to
exhale in life. We'll come to this
matter.
Have you understood generational
patterns?
It takes a man to initiate a system
and generations that follow
are bound by a pattern and the power
perpetually flows because all you need
to do is make sure that the men are all
in that pattern. So whatever Abraham
pioneered, he pioneers lies, attracts
barren women, attracts uh fair women. He
pioneers a system of escaping to Egypt.
He he pioneers a system whereby he never
blessed his firstborn. So what happened?
The son automatically is born under a
certain pattern. So there are certain
things the son is doing not by
understanding but by conditioning.
So it will take revelation for the man
to begin to audit his life and
understand things that are happening in
my life have an origin. They don't just
happen. So if the son is not sensitive,
he still marries a parent wife, the
firstborn still misses the blessing, he
still escapes to Egypt, he still survive
with lies. Just as the father pioneered
the system, the matter becomes complex
in the that generation. Now, Jacob
perfects the matter. Two barren wives.
Jacob survives by lying. Lie to Esau,
lie to Isaac. Everybody that he meets on
the way, he survived by lies. Because
there is an ancient conditioning
in the spirit.
Now, what happens
if what the Lord does is that he can
decide to lift a man in that family. And
I'll say there are three things that
this man can carry. One, the man can be
a victim.
Two, the man can also be a a a freedom
fighter. Number three, the man can rise
by revelation. So what happens is that
because there is an Asian pattern
operating, what the Lord begins by doing
is meeting a man of that bloodline.
because I cannot redeem this bloodline
because I have no legality to redeem the
bloodline. So the Lord must select a man
in the bloodline that he can partner
with. So there is a demonic switch that
has been switched on and by that switch
going on, power has to flow. Hallelujah.
So all of you face this side. All of you
face this side and then if the man faces
this side that power will continue to
flow. Whatever he gives birth to will
continue to flow. So what happens when a
man dies as a freedom fighter? This is
what happens. The Lord terms the man to
stand as a wall in the spirit so that
whatever has been flowing finds a
barrier
>> and then now now let let me have two
more people. Let me have two more
people.
Thank you. So this is the power that has
been flowing. It finds a barrier and
guess what? Now the power cannot flow
anymore. So any child born after this
man, they are not bound to the patterns
that affected the family. And now
another order begins in the spirit. And
we now begin to see whatever affected
this lineage cannot affect this lineage.
But please be careful. It took a man to
pioneer a pattern. So if this lineage,
we are not sensitive. This man, remember
now we are struggling with these things.
This man has now began well. The son has
continued well. The son disagrees with
his wife and he divorces. What happens?
He has already pioneered another
pattern.
A man goes to a witch and opens a door
in the spirit and pioneers a pattern of
poverty.
That's why being born again is also
deliverance.
Do you know the Bible says, "Seek you
first the kingdom of God and his
righteousness."
And his righteousness. Do you know what
the psalmist said? I have never seen the
righteous forsaken neither seeking nor
begging nor his children begging for
bread. Then he says, "And his
righteousness." And then the scripture
there says, "And these things will be
added." But the psalmist gives us the
revelation that I have never seen the
righteous forsaken neither begging
because when you are righteous according
to Matthew there is supply
but the righteousness of a man does not
affect the man only it also affects his
children. So what is the will of God
that whatever God pioneers in this
family is the one that has to continue.
Now this is what we call deliverance of
a bloodline that you can locate. There
were certain patterns of alcohol. There
were certain patterns of marriages.
There were certain patterns of poverty.
But when you locate the lineage, a man
rose and the pattern ended or a man
stood as a barrier and the pattern
ended. Or a man suffered. Are you
getting me? A man suffered but because
of his suffering he stands as a block
and he says it cannot happen to another
man. I will be the last to suffer this
thing and automatically because of
legality of knowledge he begins to raise
his children and prophesy to them and
make declarations and make rulings in
the spirit wages spiritual warfare and
these powers are frustrated. They can't
travel any longer. That's why when we
begin to pray for some of our children,
it is not ordinary prayer. You begin to
pray for them according to the lineage
they are coming from because they are
things that can pursue your son.
A child is growing innocently, but you
begin to see certain manifestations
and you're like, "No, this is beyond
habit. This is a transference of certain
ordination.
Do you know I I I I sat down and and Dr.
Edin is here clinical psychiatrist
and will tell you
there is a real of alcoholism
which is beyond people loving alcohol
but it is a pattern in our DNA.
Do you know all of us can take alcohol
and after one year some of us quit and
some people cannot quit not because they
don't have self-will because they come
from a lineage where that there was an
alteration of the DNA that that they are
so predisposed to addiction of alcohol
more than other people.
There are people who drink and cry and
they begin to say,
"If you go to a clinician to tell you
and you begin to study the patterns,
you'll discover it is beyond moral. It's
an attack."
Is it true? Because he works with
rehabs. He will tell you there are
people who drink and
And then you begin to ask the man, "Who
are you named after?"
And then he tells you, "My grandfather
used to run an alcoholic distribution
center."
And then you're like, "Uh, all my uncles
have been wasted by this thing. No man
in the lineage of my father is alive
because of alcohol." And that's the
lineage I was named after. And you begin
to tell the man this is beyond morals.
This now is a place where you need to
take it spiritually and tell the Lord
calibrate my DNA. Change this pattern
and configuration in my system because
salvation is being born again. You can
get a new DNA.
>> You can get a DNA that is not
predisposed to alcoholic addiction.
>> Yes, sir.
There are realms of addictions. You go
to rehabs, they will tell you there are
realms of addictions that are not in the
level of behavior.
Clinically, they will tell you this
level is in the realm of spiritual
matters. And some of the most successful
rehabs are the rehabs that have
incorporated spirituality with their
curriculums
because they understand that there is a
faculty of man that is a spirit and that
faculty can dispense certain energies
and sort the faculty of the brain.
Tell your neighbor generational patterns
I don't know where you're located
yourself. So the Lord the man rises and
he says no other single mother will ever
rise in this house. My daughters will be
married in church and their marriages
will stand. They are not married. They
are now in Sunday school. But you begin
to make declarations because you have
discovered it was not a mistake of the
man you married. When now you audit
matters outside marriage, you can begin
to see some things and discover no we
couldn't have disagreed on such a silly
matter.
Because when emotions are low and people
settle, sometimes they look back and
say, "No, I think whatever we disagreed
upon, I don't think that's the matter.
This must have been deeper. May the Lord
open up your eyes." The fact that it has
happened, it doesn't mean life is over.
There are times we rise and wait and
tell the devil, "You could have struck
me, but you're not striking another when
I'm still alive. I rise with all that is
in me to make sure that this matter ends
with me. I'm going to switch off that
battle in the spirit and this power will
never flow. And by the time you're
making those instant sessions, a few
years later, you are walking your
daughter down the aisle and saying,
"This one will work. This is the seed of
my prayer. This marriage is going to
work." And by the time you enter into
glory, you realize marriages were
restored because someone stood in their
day and waged a good warfare. We don't
live for ourselves.
We don't live for ourselves. We live for
an assignment that is greater than than
me, myself and I.
Someone will look back and realize
pastor I have seen this and he receives
a revelation. He's not a victim. But now
these are the men that they know. They
can see the power trying to manifest and
they have to announce three days of
prayer because if I don't generate
capacity in the spirit, I know these
powers want to rise. And let me tell you
the people that rise in revelation and
they trying to rely the history it will
not be easy because what the devil does
is release power and walk out. So he
knows in the family of a pastor they
will all die with diabetes marriages
will never work. So those things will
work. So all he does is supervise. How
the spirits are managing. So by the time
you lift your head there will be
questions in the demonic realm. Who does
he think that he is? This family is
ordained to stay in poverty. This family
is ordained to suffer. Who does he think
that is he? And there will be a
conglomeration of demonic powers trying
to fight you. But I bless the Lord.
There is also a witness and
conglomeration of power. It is not by
might nor by power but by my spirit says
the Lord. So when we rise, we don't rise
by our might. We enter into the quarters
of eternity and begin to call the name
of the Lord and tell the Lord, "Lord,
arise that your enemies may be
scattered." We are not fighting a losing
battle. We are redeeming the bloodline
that is shall be captured in your day.
When they mention the name Anthony, you
don't hear patterns of poverty. When
they mention the name Mary, you don't
hear patterns of witches. You hear
intercessors, prophets, pastors,
apostles. Because the system shifted in
the realms of the spirit. When they
mention your name, they discovered this
is where the matter ended. His story was
rewritten here. May the Lord open up
your eyes. May the Lord give you
understanding. May the Lord give you
revelation. May may the devil never
partner with you to open any legality in
the spirit. Stand as a guard. A
generation is waiting on your standing.
[Music]
This salvation is beyond going to
heaven. They are serious operation in
this real.
They are serious. You know, I always
take time to observe my children
because I know there there is behavior,
there is habit and there's ordination.
So anytime I sense manifestation of
certain things that I don't agree with,
I know this one I can't remove with a
cane.
I can't remove with a cane. And let me
explain this.
When I was reading yesterday night, I
couldn't sleep.
Sometimes
the Holy Spirit has a habit of when I
put when I finish writing notes, he
begins to download. So, I'm in my bed,
I'm turning, and he's still speaking.
And and when I was there, something
struck my spirit.
And what came in my spirit is that
generational patterns,
they also exist because of generational
iniquity and generational curses.
Remember,
a pattern is a repeated sequence that
allows power to do what? To flow. And
part of the triggers of certain patterns
is generational iniquity and
generational curses. I'm trying to
summarize.
Have you understood how a pattern works?
Have you understood how a pattern work?
Some of you, the Lord is going to raise
you as a freedom fighter. Please don't
stop praying. Don't stop praying. You
may not see the changes now but the Lord
is relying on your prayers because there
are children being born at the covering
of your prayer. Your uncles may not get
born again but there is a generation
rising and your prayers acts as a
preservation. Is someone getting me?
Because I've had people who come and say
pastor I've prayed I've given seeds in
the realms of the spirit. We don't know
how God delivers but we know God
delivers. He can deliver by one. He can
also deliver by many. But what I know a
burden comes upon a man and you begin to
t because of your family knowing and
knowing that all these prayers are not
in vain. One day you will enter glory
and begin to see cousins that were born
people you didn't know succeeding and
you're like thank you Jesus I prayed for
them. The Lord is looking for a man to
stand in the gap for the sake of their
family.
Hallelujah.
What I'm teaching you is also personal
to me. I've done a few investigations in
my family and I know a few things. So
I'm not teaching you how will I say from
a place of theology. Neither am I
teaching you from a place of I'm 70
years and now I'm teaching you from a
place of I'm also learning them and
applying them.
Okay.
Sometimes people will come and ask you
are there diseases in your bloodline?
What is that? It's a pattern.
You are eating healthy. Suddenly someone
tells you you have diabetes.
All your life you have been healthy and
then now they begin to introduce you to
certain diets. You know it is okay. And
then you begin to hear you know your
great grandmother died of it, your
auntie died of it, your father and you
look at it and begin to say no Lord this
diabetes has a source.
It is not you who planted it because
you're not an author of diseases. It has
a source.
Oh, this arthritis has a source.
And those are the men that I'm raising.
We will testify on this land that
diialysis is not what is going to keep
us. God can give me new kidneys
>> and reverse whatever they call whatever
whatever causes sugar not to balance.
Is he not the creator?
So, so we are not just here to write
notes. We are here to get prayer points.
Lift up your hands in the name of Jesus.
>> Anything that travels by blood,
>> by DNA in my father's house,
>> by the reason of redemption and
salvation, I declare I'm exempted.
So,
so doctors will ask you
and it is key to know them so that you
know what you're dealing with. But as
you it's good to have understanding, you
know, you know, I was with pastor Morris
shared something
about there are certain levels of
afflictions
that are demonic
and maturity are. And he shared with me
what sitting in the vest tree we made a
prayer to somebody and then he he now
explained he said you know a a demon and
that's why sometimes when you're doing
deliverance it worsens then it loses.
Sometimes you hear someone cry and then
they relapse and then the thing leaves
because a demon can come and hold your
lungs.
You go to hospital and they tell you
it's asthma.
So you take all the asthma medication
and then later you hear it never left.
The thing is still there. Test are being
run. At that level you need to
understand it's not asthma. A spirit has
hanged on your lungs. So unless it is
cast out,
you will enter many hospitals and they
cannot sort you out.
A spirit can hang in your stomach and
every time you're surviving with anti-
acidic medicines.
We've done test on your stomach linings.
No problem. You're healthy. But there
are these reactions at that level. No,
something keeps on has attached itself.
And sometimes even at certain
frequencies of prayer that thing can
manifest. You begin to feel stomach
disorders because that thing has entered
an environment it cannot stand. It's
just waiting an order of come out
because they survive by orders.
Don't you understand why we say come
out? We don't see them but we can see
the manifestation in a man's body. And
now we the Bible says casting them out.
Do you know why? Do you know demons rely
on the man casting them out? They rely
on that instruction.
The day my wife had a demonic attack.
She woke up and her stomach was
cringing.
My wife has never told me to take her to
hospital. That time she told me, "No,
let's go to the hospital." And then the
Holy Spirit told me, "Speak in tonesues
by the time you're in Kabeta, the thing
will leave because we're going to
Kikuyo." So I spoke in tongues, but the
thing left when we arrived in Kikuyo. So
I asked him, "Was it not Kabet?" He
said, "No, you're overdriving." So,
there was a speed. I was meant to drive
cuz now when your wife is hurting, you
step on that thing and and let me tell
you that thing left. We were praying in
tongues and she said, "I feel such a
relief." Now, because we had called
nurse Grace and she was there. So, we
went to say hi to her
because now we had woken her up late and
when they checked, nothing was there. It
was an attack. Some pains that come to
you at night and they stay there. No,
no, no. Lay your hands and speak in
tongues.
Command it to leave. Even some
manifestations on our children. No. You
hold that child and say in the name of
Jesus, you demonic power, you have no
authority. Loosen this child.
>> We are teaching you to operate under
authority. There are certain
manifestation that they are not
diseases. You know, we have been
cultured to see life with the lenses of
medicine. We need to see life in the
lenses of spirituality. You'll begin to
understand the man who look at the
behavior of the lank and say this is
lemonia. But after taking lemonia drugs,
nothing is happening. You know this is
not lemonia. This is a demon manifesting
as lemonia.
>> The Bible says there was a spirit that
had attacked a young man and that young
manifested epilepsy.
>> He manifested epilepsy. According to
medical manifestation, the spirit will
seize the man and throw him in the fire
and the man will form in his mouth. And
the father knew it is epilepsy.
>> But when Jesus came, he said it is not
epilepsy. The name of this spirit is you
damp and mute dumb and deaf spirit. So
he had accuracy. And that's why Jesus
said such kind cannot come unless by
fasting and prayer because it can
manifest as epilepsy. But the real name
is dump
>> and death. So it can manifest as
pneumonia. But the real name is a spirit
of death.
>> That's why you say this kind. What is
that kind? The one that has the ability
to camouflage and behave
>> like stomach. But deep down is a spirit
that is designed to shorten your life.
So you look at it and say you have no
authority over my life. And I want to
announce over people that have been
having attacks of diseases. Today by
this revelation I want to declare no
demonic power will ever arrest you ever.
I command any attack in your belly, on
your back, on your neck, on your joints,
anything that keeps on coming and going
back, coming and going back, I declare
from today it will never manifest again.
I command that spirit of affliction to
live your life.
So there is a level patterns cannot
survive without curses and iniquity.
We have read about Reuben. Are we
together? We have read about Reuben. So
let's assume this is Reuben. His cast.
So who will suffer the effect of that
cast? A curse is a pronunciation of
doom.
How do curses operate?
The real of the spirit answers to words.
A man can die, but words don't die.
Words don't die. So a man died and he
looked at my father. He looked at this
man and said,
"None of your children will ever go
anywhere." So remember or you you will
never prosper. You'll never succeed. So
the curse is upon the man. Reuben was
told that he's unstable. And scripture
says anytime the tribe of Reuben went to
war, they the most died. They will go a
thousand men 200 from Reuben. The tribe
of Reuben will lose more soldiers.
Now a generation is suffering. There is
a pattern of suffering because there is
a curse that was released. A curse is a
word and demons are very good in
implementing words.
You see when you look at the pattern of
creation because I keep on telling you
the demonic world is not new. It is a
replica of the spiritual world. When God
looked upon the waters, the Holy Spirit
could only hoover. There's nothing the
Holy Spirit could implement.
But when a word proceeded from Zion,
things began to change. So spirits are
perpetually waiting for words they can
implement.
Because they work with words.
That's why I love what Bishop JB said.
Even our careless talks will be judged
because you have already released a
word. And let me also help you please.
Some of the confessions you keep on
making that are negative, they empower
the demonic to implement your confession
cuz spirits cannot operate until words
are pronounced.
I read a book and it said the original
intention for words was not
communication but creation.
So what are your words creating?
People are talking today about energies.
Let me even go further. Some of some do
you know I always know when I'm
trending.
I can be in America, but I'll know how.
I always sense
a heaviness
and a demonic sorrow.
Because when a thousand people are
speaking ill of you,
those words travel as energies
and they begin to generate a certain
atmosphere over your life. So sometimes
I don't need to go online. I I will just
sense things are not okay and then you
go online and you hear someone has
pulled an old video taken something
misreented everything you said and then
you see people now sharing opinions and
you know Kenyans have opinions and many
of them are not very good opinions and
they will insult you, attack you see and
the moment words are released they
cannot be called back. So they now it is
either you neutralize them by applying
Isaiah 54 condemning every tongue raised
against you so that you begin to
neutralize the words that were released.
When we come to the game of words
silence is not humility you will die.
>> Words can even enter a level and
manifest as an infirmity. Sometimes you
begin to feel pains on your back and
your neck and you don't know at that
level maybe they are aunties discussing
about your wedding and they are not
saying good things they are beginning to
declare negative things and that
atmosphere generated begins to manifest
in your life you may not know it
sometimes you are not mood swinging you
just woke up but there is a certain
demonic heaviness you don't understand
it ah by that time you know there is a
gathering somewhere
that's why don't deceived. Some of these
celebrities when they begin to parade
money online, it is a language of
brokenness because they have been
insulted. People have spoken about them
and the only thing they can hold is
either their money or they are curs.
That is the only thing. So they will
come and parade money and say you you
abusing me and you're a bedsitter. Get
alive. When you take away that money,
that man has nothing to hold. And some
of them when they go back to their
homes, they are depressed.
You cannot trend and tell me you'll come
and smile and say I don't care. That's a
plastic face. Words will affect you
without asking for your permission.
That's why sometimes you react and drive
your big car and begin to say see these
poor people abusing me and they in their
bed seats. The problem is not per se.
It's a reaction of the atmosphere they
have generated over you. It is so toxic.
Please don't be the one that makes
people get depressed online.
If a whole president of a nation can
quit online,
>> a president who has C, DCI,
judiciary, military, but he cannot run
away from opinions and statements made
on X and he comes and says social media.
What do you think that
You wake up, 2 million people have
insulted you.
>> Cartoons are trending all over and they
are not saying good things about you.
[Music]
You can even come there for a week to
hear what a man said. Imagine now people
have shared 10,000 opinions and they are
not okay. Sometimes I see people
trending and I pray for them because I
know the power of words. Whether you
hate them or you don't hate them, I know
what it means to an individual. That's
why people get depressed. That's why
some of the celebrities, they cannot
afford to be sober because how do you
face life reality when your senses are
working? You just need to be
intoxicated.
So many times and I sense
therapy.
The agenda of those words will not
prevail. I diffuse them. I scatter them.
I nullify them. I break them and I wake
up because the scripture has given me
authority.
>> So I don't need to go and respond
online. No, you don't respond online.
You respond in the spirit. and the
impact will be felt on the ground. This
is a spiritual matter.
>> I called a friend of mine and I told him
sir, you are not just trending. There's
an attack over your authority and your
voice.
Do you know if if today I I declare
uh I'm selling me tumbas.
Let me tell you what's happening. The
attack in the church right now. I saw
something in America where they have
arrested a preacher 65 years old for a
mistake he did when he was 18 and he was
not a pastor at 18.
At 18
years
sex didn't happen but the lady was
mishandled in an inappropriate way. So
the man of God is now 65.
The lady has sued the man of God saying,
"I was I was mishandled when I was 12.
This thing has caused damage in my
emotions from that time. I've lost my
marriages. I've been in a in chaos." And
then the man went and said, "It's okay.
It's true. I did it. He has not been
sentenced for 6 months." Now, first of
all, I sat down. I said at 18, Rashid,
how many things did you do? None of us
should be preaching here. None of us
should be holding this mic. But you see
the way the media now fabricated it, the
media never even said that this thing
happened almost 50 years ago. The media
says a 65 year old preacher has been
sentenced for inappropriately sexually
mishandling a 12y old. That's the
headline. Now in in that nation you need
to understand the the people pushing the
agenda of the LGBTQ. No, their greatest
opponent is the church. So what do we
do? Let us discredit the voice of the
church. So that when the church says
this is bad, we tell them you are raping
children. You have no right to tell us
this is bad.
>> Am I opening anyone's eye? So sometimes
you think it's just a pastor trending.
But when you begin to search the details
of that pastor, you realize this man of
God has been advocating certain matters
that no one wants to talk about. Now the
devil must wage warfare not on the man
but on his voice. How do you fight his
voice? Assassinate his character. So by
the time he stands to say this and this
and this is wrong, you begin to pull a
file of rumors and things you had online
and vindicate the man. This is the
persecution of the end time church. We
will not be hanged physically but men
will hang us on Twitter.
>> So we better be ready because it's
either we keep quiet and the generation
dies or we die preaching because even if
you kill us our words will still live.
>> So we cannot keep quiet because we are
afraid. Oh this one will say this one
will say no we will also live living
words.
The apostles died but they left their
>> So a cast tell your neighbor a curse is
a statement that wishes people do. So
you see Reuben curses is cast and curses
are very mysterious because you can also
have what I call territorial curses.
Joshua 6:26. A territory can be cast.
You can enter territory that is cast.
I'm about to finish Joshua 6:26. Joshua
cast Jericho
and he said Joshua cast Jericho. Look at
Joshua 6. Are you understanding
something this day? Thank you. Joshua
6:26 media please. Then Joshua ch them
at that time saying cast be the man
before the Lord who raises up and builds
this city Jericho. He shall lay his
foundation with his first born and with
his youngest he shall set up its gate.
Are you seeing the curse and the details
of the curse? Look at first kings 16:34.
A man attempted to build and Joshua
who's an anointed general had released a
cast. So the territory was undercast.
Joshua 1 16:34
one
first kings.
Everybody read in his days he held of
Bethl built Jericho. He laid his
foundation with Abiram, his firstborn,
and with his youngest son, Seub. He set
up his gate according to the word of the
Lord, which had been spoken through. So,
a a territory was cast, and a man
decided to go against the cast, and the
details of the cast worked against him.
It took Elisha, 2 Kings,
I think verse two from 19 to 22, 2 Kings
2. It took Elisha, a man that carried a
double anointing of Elijah to revoke the
curse that was upon Jericho. 2 Kings
2 Kings 2:19-22,
is it 2 or 3? Elisha came and he said,
"The city is good, but the waters are
bitter. Anyone that drinks of the water
miscarriages."
Then the men of the city said, "Please
notice the situation of this city. It's
uh the city is pleasant as my loss is
bad. The water is bad and the ground
barren." And this is where people began
the ministry of salt.
And he said, "Bring me a new bowl and
put salt in it." So they brought it to
him. If you are not Elisha, leave this
prophetic symbol.
And if you want to fulfill all prophetic
symbols of the Bible, then the day the
Lord will tell you to preach judgment,
go and walk naked like Ezekiel.
We can't pick some and leave others and
then build doctrines on some.
from today.
I saw a meme going around
of a person who had gone to hell and the
devil was asking him how are you
fighting me and he was told now do it
and the man will pick salt and say
scatter scatter and the devil will laugh
and ask him do it again because he's not
afraid of salt he's afraid of the blood
of Jesus
then he went on to the source of the
water and cast it in the salt there and
says thus says the lord I have healed
this water from it there shall be no
more death or perilousness The land was
healed. There is a city in Uganda called
Ginger
meant to be an industrial city. They
went and there was a big crusade.
Rainard Bonke was meant to preach there.
On the day of the preaching, they went
and took the man out of stage, kicked
him out. He was taken in a very violent
way. The man fulfilled the scripture,
shook his dust. The city has never
recovered up to date.
It is supposed to be the industrial city
of ginger. So now imagine you have a
business idea and you go to a territory
that bears a curse. So the problem is
not industrialization.
The problem is the c must be lifted for
the city to prosper.
Am I speaking to anyone? So, so, so
where there is a cast there will be
patterns of certain things but someone
spoke like I know I met a man and it was
so bad because that man the father was
alive. This is a true story because it
is a place we had bought property. So
the father is alive and the man goes and
divides a portion and says this is my
portion and he pours building material
and the elders tell the man when he's
sick and alive are you building and he
says no then he asked what's happening
and was told oh it is your son who has
taken a part of the property uh and he
has begun to build he says that part I
had purposed to give him but I have not
yet given him and he said because of
what he has done that property will
never help him. And these were his
words. It is the street boys who will be
helping themselves there. So we go, we
are looking for property. We buy the
next property and we try to negotiate
with the guy to sell the property but
something
something just comes and brings a dead
end. I was told the last time they even
signed a sale agreement and they agreed
we are selling at this amount. On the
day of payment, the man pulled out and
the property is prime. And guess what?
The people that work there are
mechanics. And that's where street
children help themselves. The man died.
But the realities of his words are
there.
Pastor, how do you deal with curses?
This is the reality. We have a word that
is above your grandfather's word.
>> The eldership of God is superior than
the eldership of your grandfather.
So what comes are two there are two
principles when it comes to curses.
Number one in the book of proverbs I'm
trying to look for it. It says a curse
without a cause has no landing. A curse
without a cause. Deuteronomy 26 and
verse two. This is the way out of any
curse. Number one, Proverbs 26 and verse
two.
Proverbs 26 and:2, please. Proverbs 26
and:2. And then you prepare Deuteronomy
33:6.
The one who's there
next so that we go quickly.
Everybody read
please. Let's read like
TP
your latest
directly to English
simplified English
scroll
because I want to show you something.
Some of you, you have entertained words
that were spoken, but in the realms of
the spirit, you need to rise as an
authority and cancel them. An
undisturbed curse will be powerless to
pastor. Every time my father comes home
drunk, he calls us prostitutes. That is
an undeserved curse. There is no ground
for his weddings. His bitterness is his
own issue.
Sorry. His bitterness is his own. But
that does not mean you keep quiet. You
rise with Proverbs 26 and say the words
of my father have no ground to learn. I
cannot be a prostitute and I nullify
those words in the real of the spirit.
It may flatter over you like a bird but
it will find no place to land. Meaning
that it cannot find a place of
realization. So system number one audit
the source of the curse. Was it
legitimate? Was it genuine? Was there a
ground? If there was a ground, what do
you do? Let's assume my grandfather c my
father and now I'm here in that
generation. I'm suffering. I'm poor
because nobody succeeds. There was a
word released. What you do at that
level? You pray the prayers of
identification. You come and approach
your God. You you approach your father
or your grandfather cast as the one that
was cast. A good example. So my father
repent.
I come and I say I I I messed I wronged
my grandfather and I messed and because
of that my grandfather spoke a word and
I'm suffering and now I repent for the
wrong and by this repentance the
legality of the curse is nullified
whether the grandfather is alive or not
you just release a repentance it's
called repentance by identification
and when you make prayer. The words that
were released have no ground to affect
your life.
The second way to lift a c is
Deuteronomy 33 and:E6.
There are certain authorities that can
bless you also.
It was Moses that lifted the curse in
the house of Reuben.
When Jacob spoke, he was an authority.
He was a father. When Moses spoke, he
spoke as another authority. This is what
Moses declared. Let Reuben live and not
die, nor let his men be filled. That's
why anytime we are doing children
dedication, I will always call the woman
and I'll call if the woman comes without
a father, I'll always call a man as an
authority to stand as a father and
release fatherly blessings.
And even if that man has no stature, by
the prayers I make on the altar to that
child, the blessings of the father will
come upon that child. Is someone getting
me? Yes. So if your father is not
around, never spoke any word, we now
come to the covenantal blessings of
Elohim.
The other way that these things are
broken, curses that have been hoovering
over your life, you begin to declare the
word of God over your life. Why? The
word of God is ancient than the words of
your grandfather. The word of God is
powerful and more effective than the
words of a man that died. You now begin
to become a man that lives by
declaration. I am blessed. I am favored.
I cannot be cast.
I know the Bible says because Jesus hung
on the cross, cast is the man that hangs
on the cross.
And I know when we teach new creation
reality, we tell men you cannot be cast.
It is true. But we need to understand
the context of that scripture. It was
not a curse as unto statement. It was a
curse as unto the law. The book of
Deuteronomy carries the blessings of the
law and the curses of the law. So if you
didn't keep the law, the curses became
your portion. So because the Lord
nullified the law, he also nullified the
curses of the law. So anyone that lives
by Mosaic covenant is a candidate of
that cast. But the cast I'm talking
about is the cast that the one Jacob
spoke over Ruben. It took an authority
to nullify the words in the atmosphere.
And that's why now once in a while when
we begin to say now I declare. Sometimes
we are dealing with matters that were
announced and that's the way you receive
your miracle. The second thing you now
begin to declare the word of God. And if
there was a cause for the curse, go and
ask for permission.
She never said any words. But those
tears are a curse. You try everything in
the city. Nothing succeeds. Go and
repent and let the woman say, "I've
forgiven you." And see how things will
happen. Because there are two
authorities that three can that speak a
blessing. One, the first authority is a
parent. The second is a priest. The
third is a leader. Kings used to bless
nations.
One day I saw the president saying, "I
bless Kenya." We may not, we may have
different varying opinions, but the
office spoke and the Bible gives him
permission to bless the land. Kings used
to bless nations.
The blessing of a father cannot be
acquired by a priest and the blessing of
a priest cannot be delivered by a
father.
Disconnect toxic
cut off
that language
A story is told of an old man and uh his
son and his grandchild and the father
the the the the the the
old man. So So we have an old man and
this is his son and this is the
grandson. So the son felt this man is
becoming a burden. So he decided to take
him with his grandson to the home of the
elderly.
from today. This will be a home.
The son asked the father, "Daddy,
the man turned the car." He went and
took the grandfather and said, "Whatever
I'm modeling is a seed I'm sewing for
myself."
Where we cut off Mama Kabisa. One day,
one day you will carry someone for 9
months. You will know the pains of
labor. You will know the pains of
breastfeeding, sticking with a child
until the child becomes mature. You will
know the pains of school fees. You will
know the pain of the economy. And then
that child will come visiting day. You
are coming to visit the child and the
child snobs you. You remember the tears
of that woman you're saying you're
cutting off. The things people are
trying to do. Oh, mom keeps on asking me
for money. Can I tell you blessing your
parents is a blessing. Don't cut that
door of blessing. How do I know that? My
doors opened because I I I keep on
blessing my grandmother. She will take
the money and say
and I cannot be poor because those words
coordinate provision over my life. Don't
get tired to support those men. The
words they ut yeah when they say may God
bless you. I know it may be
uncomfortable and that's why the Bible
says there will be long life because you
cannot die before you see the blessings
of their utterance. The Bible says honor
your parents. The language of honor has
the language of money. This is not to
say parents are quite insensitive.
30,000
10k killer time. You take a part of it
as a seed of honor and tell the Lord,
Lord, this is what I can afford from my
heart and I'm giving my mom because I
love her. Whatever she will speak after
I send that word will not attack me and
release it and fulfill your side because
I know there are parents who budget for
their children money. This is true.
So tell your neighbor, wisdom is key.
It's so it's it's a blessing when you
see your children prosper and when when
you receive receive with thanksgiving.
Some of us in this Nairobi we don't we
don't even know what three meals mean.
It's two meals
heavy breakfast heavy supper lunch by
the way
service
You know Jesus said your will is my
food.
4 hours before tell that neighbor
neighbor from today by this revelation
the Lord is raising you as a switch in
the spirit to switch off the powers of
darkness and switch on another order.
Next Sunday we'll check on
next Sunday we'll still build on that
matter because I want us to check now on
what I call generational iniquity is
something I really want to address
because
and it can be inherent.
It can be transferred
and and and and
through that we'll be able also to
understand how to deal with it and even
the patterns that it causes.
Because
when the sons of Eli mishandled the
offering, the Lord said, "None of these
children shall rise to the age of
maturity." So that means they all died
less than 30 years because of a certain
error their father committed.
Wu can also be territorial. will deal
with matters of
do kikuyos love money
are los proud.
Is that stereotyping? Can we quantify
through research and say it is true? So
is it possible to have community
iniquity
that a whole city called Sodom is gay?
And anyone that tries to be a virgin and
is a man cannot survive. And some of the
things that this community iniquities
begin to do even to a territory.
Look at even as an own individual
inherent things
and some of the things that iniquity can
do to a man is something that I want to
touch on because it will also help us to
understand that we can a a parent I was
praying and then the Lord told me a
parent can open a door and a parent can
also become a door. So how that parent
handles himself matters a lot. And this
is a matter that once we understand
we'll be able to do many things. Is it
okay for me to go and steal county money
so that my children can go and study in
America? So the baser given for the
poor, I steal it and pay school fees for
my child in America. Then two years
later, my child is a drug addict because
the cries of these children are
beginning to interfere with that
operation.
I buy my son a car with pesa Sunday
school the next thing
as a father I've opened a door of attack
because sometimes it looks like I want
to love my children at the expense of of
other people
and many have destroyed generations s
without understanding.
Let us stand up on our feet. I want to
bless you.
I want to bless you. Please stand to
that neighbor. Tell that neighbor,
neighbor
teaching
deliverance.
Hallelujah. I just want Have you learned
something?
>> Is it helpful?
Lift up your hands.
Father
in the name of Jesus,
you have brought this understanding at
such a time
because there are people under the sound
of my voice that are going to pioneer
new orders of families.
There are people at the sound of my
voice that are going to begin
new patterns that are connected to the
Holy Spirit. May this become a building
block over their lives. May this become
a revelation
so that they can be able to turn around
matters in their lives. And now I
declare
any generational pattern that has
manifested over your life, I declare by
this revelation, let it come to an end,
receive the grace to divert it, to turn
it around and to change the narrative.
Anything that has manifested or is
trying to manifest or is trying to show
up in your life, I release the grace of
God, the power of the Holy Ghost, may
you conquer it. May you overcome it. May
you change the tangents. May you change
the dynamics in the mighty name of
Jesus. Anyone that has been a victim,
you will not die there. Arise and
rewrite the history. Let the past be the
past. Don't look at the wounds and the
scars. Stand as a warrior and contend
for the generations that are coming.
Them that have received this re
revelation, some in marriage, some not
even married, may the Lord give you the
wisdom to understand the bigger picture
in the mighty name of Jesus. And now if
there be anyone under the sound of my
voice who is a product of a curse,
people spoke, authority spoke, I now
stand as Moses where Moses stood, I
declare you are blessed. Every word
uttered over your life, I cancel it. I
nullify it. I destroy it. I declare it
has no legality of operation. It has no
power. spirits that have been using the
words to implement realities over your
life. I declare from this hour, you are
blessed and not cast. You are blessed
and not cast. You are favored. You are
under the cannopy of the word of God.
You are a child of God. You are
surrounded by the fire of the Holy
Ghost. Anything that tried to manifest
because of ignorance by this revelation,
it has no power to manifest over your
life.
Every curse uttered without a cause.
Assemblies where people gather
pronouncing our names, releasing
utterances
according to the book of Proverbs, I
declare they have no landing ground.
They have no place of manifestation.
They have no room of a manifestation.
And every assembly that rises against
you online on ground, people that try to
fight you by the authority of the name
of Yeshua, their assignment will not
prevail. We overrule the rule of the
rulers. We overturn the tables of the
decision makers in the mighty name of
Jesus. People that gather to speak
against your business, against your
children, against your marriage, against
your career. People are perpetually
talking. And now we are talking on this
altar. They are words will not prevail,
but the word of God over your life shall
come to pass.
The opinion of men concerning your
children will never prevail. People look
at us and they say,
We want to declare those words will
never have any place of manifestation. I
will live and not die. I will see the
goodness of the Lord in the land of the
living. I will stand on mountain tops to
declare the goodness of the Lord. May
that be your portion in the mighty name
of Jesus.
Lift up your hand and say, "No curse can
manifest over my life. I am too blessed
to be cast.
>> I am too blessed to be cast.
>> Declare in the name of Jesus,
>> every word,
>> every word
>> spoken against my life,
>> I neutralize you now.
>> I neutralize your operation
>> and your function.
>> And I declare I am blessed. I am
favored. I am victorious. I am a
success. I am above only. My path
shineth brighter and brighter like the
breaking of the dawn. The work of my
hands is blessed. My career is blessed.
My family is blessed. My children are
blessed. I am blessed in the name of
Jesus. Hallelujah.
Hallelujah.
It cannot be otherwise. I say it cannot
be otherwise.
>> May you stand like this man to change
the narrative in your family. May that
be your portion that the children that
will come, the generation that will come
after you will what the Bible calls the
seed of the rashers. The seed of the
Russians. Please tell that neighbor,
neighbor, God is waiting on you to
rewrite the history of your family in
Jesus name. Before we sit down, I want
to ask if you're here and you're not
born again, I want to make that prayer
because we are moving to a very brief
session. But I want to ask you if you're
here and you're not born again, please
lift up your hand
and I'm going to pray for you.
Oh, thank you. Thank you.
We say this this operation is called as
for me and my house.
as for me and my house.
Oh, thank you Jesus.
Thank you Holy Ghost. Let's celebrate
the Lord.
There is harvest in the house.
Worshippers, you can come. Anyone else?
There is another brother. There is
another brother.
Thank you, Holy Ghost. Hallelujah.
Hallelujah.
Celebrate the Lord.
Celebrate Jesus.
[Music]
There is a sister coming. There are more
coming. There are more coming. Put your
hands together for Jesus. There is
harvest in the house.
[Music]
Let us celebrate the Lord. Thank you my
sister.
[Music]
>> Anyone else? Today is the day.
>> If you're there and you're not born
again, run to the altar.
>> Run to the altar.
Run to the altar.
make him one.
So,
[Music]
thank you Jesus.
[Applause]
Hallelujah.
>> More are coming.
>> More are coming to the Lord.
to all
to
>> give
So
to
[Music]
me,
I read something and it said
statistics are showing that Many Gen Z
young men are responding to Jesus.
When the priesthood is restored,
the families are healed.
>> Hallelujah.
God is doing something in this land.
There is a healing that will happen even
in families to come because when a young
man knows the Lord, he will lift and
raise his family in the ways of the
Lord. They say 90%
of homes where the father is born again,
the wife and the children will will
always go to church. So the Lord is
realigning the order in our generation.
This is a sign of how God is healing
families.
By beginning to get the men and the
priest. Hallelujah. Man, I'm so happy.
Just lift up your hands to the Lord and
I want you to pray this prayer. You are
here because you believe. It is not the
prayer that saves. It is the faith that
has brought you here. Say, "Lord Jesus,
today I have heard your word and now
knowing that I'm a sinner and I cannot
save myself,
I come to you.
And by faith, I receive the forgiveness
of my sins. By faith, I receive eternal
life. By faith I confess with my mouth
because I believe in my heart that Jesus
you are Lord and Savior over my life.
Thank you Jesus for saving me. Father,
thank you for these men and women. Thank
you for their lives. Thank you for their
destinies. And from this hour, I declare
the yolks of darkness are broken. And I
connect you to the life of Jesus. And I
declare none of you will ever look back.
May you be filled with the Holy Ghost.
May you operate in the power of Elohim.
And may you stand to deliver your
families in Jesus name we have prayed.
Let's celebrate them once again.
[Music]
And then someone will show you where to
come and see. Just follow that guy.
Ashers, let us help them. Church, let us
celebrate them once again. Let us
celebrate Jesus.
Let us celebrate Jesus for the harvest.
Hallelujah.
Amen. We can have our seats.
We are going to do this very fast. Tell
your neighbor, neighbor,
>> today
>> is our special giving Sunday.
>> And today we are giving sacrificially.
By the time
by the time we are getting to second
week of November,
Hallelujah.
sacrificial giving. And so maybe we can
have some pictures uh media just to see
where we are
in order of gender, ladies and
gentlemen. And so I'll invite the leader
for the ladies and the leaders for the
men to come. We give our collections and
I met a few of my friends on Friday.
We are together in this in joy and in
building. So media I think you have some
photos. Amen. Amen. We can we can maybe
project the giving details especially
for the people giving online. And I want
us to do this for accountability
purposes. Are we together? Are we
together? Please project the the giving
details. This is what I want us to do.
Okay. They've already done what I wanted
them to do.
So you want all the giving to go here?
Apart from tithe. Now listen, listen.
Apart from tithe.
32 59
59 59
because we we we need to separate. that
every giving today package your offering
in that offering add your sacrificial
giving and put it together and even
those that are watching online apart
from tithe we give our tithe to 325959
any other money unless you're also
giving your tithe and you're out of the
country you can use 0726714713
so if you are here and the money we are
going to collect we're going to give you
the tabul ation on Sunday. Is that true?
So that we tell you what we've managed.
The giving detail is 50 29 929.
50 29 9 29. And guess what you're going
to see? It's still life church. So it's
not a different deal. If you need an
envelope for hard money, physical cash,
you can lift your hand and the ashers
will give it to you. If
if if you if you came with a PDQ, you
want to swap PDQ machine. Where are you?
There's one over there. Is only one.
Yeah, is one. Two. Where is the other
PDQ?
Yeah.
Holies of Holies. There's another PDQ
over there.
Please continue. If you're writing a
check, please uh write to Life Church
International
Leuru. Make sure it is captured like
that. Life Church International Leuru.
So I know the ladies ladies
are giving in your groups. Is that true?
Yes. But because I know lady group what
we are going to do ladies do you want to
come and present your giving let's do
quickly do you want to come and do it
now
mama
men who is standing on behalf of men
activity
Elijah
and priest
ladies I think there's something they
did so you can come but anyway no matter
the way of giving at the end of the day
is going to the same place is that okay
please tell that neighbor neighbor
Hallelujah. Yes. Just give her the mic
so that she can see how much we
collected from Hadasa. Let's appreciate
her.
Yeah. From Women of Power, you've been
able to put together around uh 115,000
So our treasurer will be forwarding it
to the details but the giving is still
going on. Thank you.
>> Let's put our hands together.
because they the ones who gave the women
they will give on individual level.
So anyway, the men have said they will
give on an individual level. Um,
so please let us give, let us give, let
us give. Uh, I want to appreciate the
team. You can stand.
>> Just stand.
They came, we prayed for them, they had
an amazing meeting at Tio Farm. And they
told me, "Pastor, we want to come today
and just say thank you." And now they
are going to Kikuyo uh to Nakuro.
May God give you favor with that land.
And even because of your coming, may the
Lord perfect that which concerns you.
May this sound be used to shift the
sound in the atmosphere and you are
going very far. God bless you. We are
really honored.
Amen.
Announcements
as we are giving and then after that
we'll make a prayer
and then we'll Oh, I have a magazine
here.
Doc magazine.
Hallelujah.
Somebody say Docar magazine.
300.
The money you give for this magazine is
always used to support the Doxa
conference. And today all my books are
on offer 500. If you're there and you
need the family battles book,
I'm saying this on the pullpit because
it's on a 500 offer and you can't afford
the 500, go and buy with the money you
have because I want everybody to get
that book. Is that okay?
So please if you if you have if you have
a 100 go and give it the money that
you're buying that book with that's I'm
also giving it to the Sunday school. So
whatever book you buy the project also
goes to the Sunday school. So these are
our classes as you can see our children
these are global children. You can see
how that school looks like. This does
not look like a global school. So we
must make sure that this project comes
to an end at least.
I hope
in the next two months this will be a
different story and you can see we have
so many children. We want to make sure
that every class will have its own
theme. They have 34 teachers and we'll
now move them from
we'll now move them from the
consecration and make sure every class
sits a specific number so that we pay
attention and give attention to every
student. So whatever we are giving for
is for a noble cause. Hallelujah
William
Thank you, Apostle. Um, so even as we
give, I know probably there'll be a
select group of people that might want
to um do a class by themselves. You can
see Edwin for that because I know there
are people who had expressed interest to
just take up a class by themselves and
build it up. I think we've gotten to
know the figures that takes up to do one
class till completion. Uh but I want to
give you the announcements uh very
quickly on the 7th of November. Uh that
is uh on a Friday. The couples are
having their amazing dinner. It's it's
going to be at Ellesian Resort. It's
5,500 per couple and it's going to be an
amazing time of love, laughter, and
sweet memories. So, uh, all the men,
prepare on this night to take your wives
for an amazing date at Alleian. We'll
also be having a baby dedication because
one of the things that we believe as an
apostolic ministry is you cannot baptize
children. The only thing that we can do
is to dedicate them to the Lord. So, on
the 19th of October, we'll be having
baby dedication. So for uh people who
have been blessed and their numbers have
been increased in their house and their
children have not been dedicated or you
have a child that has never been
dedicated, please if you want to do so,
please see uh Sylvia. I believe you saw
Sylvia when she stood up here uh pass
over your names so that we can plan for
the dedication. This is the last Oh, let
me just skip this one. Uh the vault
teens will be having their vault camp.
We thank God for the the teenagers.
They're doing an amazing job. So be
having their camp on the 17th to the
21st of December at Nova Pioneer. So
we're making this announcement so that
parents you can begin to prepare for
this. The cost is going to be 4,500 for
the vault camp. So when they come to you
to ask you for money, see a job, but
there's actually a camp that is
happening. And then from the Kings and
Priest Ministry, they organized an
amazing uh package. It's called a boys
to men program. It's going to be a right
of passage um held by uh in in together
in togetherness with the kings and
priests ministry. Uh the the
it will happen from the 8th of November
to the 19th of November. So, it's going
to be there for 10 days as a 10 days
program as they transition from boys to
men. And the charges are 10,000 per boy.
So, you can register with 1,000 for this
program. Uh if you would like to do so,
please see um
I want to please see uh K. Please see K.
Carl, rise up on your feet. If you want
to register for the best boys to men
program, you can see Carl or any of the
leaders in kings and priests so that we
can make sure that we have this amazing
program. And because this is also a life
church service, this is the last
wedding announcement
for John Mora and Betric Namura. Buana
you know John Mora as peach
they'll be getting married on the 17th
of October which happens to be this
Friday at the destiny grounds bonas f so
let's come in and support pish and
betric as you can see serves in the
ushering department and this is minister
pish bonas fee purity is still happening
it is continuing it will continue even
after marriage amen and why don't we
appreciate them as they have their
seats.
I also want to give a special shout out
to a certain group of people even as we
prepare to finish this service. Uh these
people have helped us make uh docu
successful. Uh this is Maisha
Developments. I believe you saw them
when they gave us their presentation. We
also have Fusion Estates. They also
supported the Doxa conference. Fusion
Estates deal with real estate. They also
have a stand outside. You can go and see
them. We have St. Paul's University. We
also have TK Creatives. TK is one of us.
He's the one who does all our graphics.
Uh thank you TK. We also have Daisy.
And then we have Marriage and Bliss. We
also have Fari Manufacturing Industries
that have partnered with us. And we also
want to appreciate in a special way
elevate TV bas all the services for doaw
were live on elevate including the
afternoon one that all of you are
invited for but in a special way I want
us to appreciate a certain group of
people. One I want to appreciate all the
workers.
These are people who spent countless
times. Some of them have required to ask
for offs from work. Some of them have
had to be here very early in the
morning. There are days I'd have to
leave here and I'd leave some of the
workers uh even after me. So please if
you are a worker in life church kindly
can you just rise up on your feet
protocol department praise and worship
uh all the people that serve security
you know there are people that don't
even attend service because they are
outside making sure that everything is
well.
Now church I want you to put your hands
together for these amazing people. These
are the pillars that ensure that the
engine in life church is running. And we
want to say thank you. Thank you media
team for always doing an amazing job.
Thank you praise and worship. Thank you
ushering and protocol. Even the kitchen
department that might not even be here
because they're working. The people that
serve in guest experience. May the Lord
bless you. May the Lord bless you. But
as we appreciate them, I want to
appreciate another group of people. This
are the people from our events. This is
Remnant Events. It's our it's our events
company. These people are the ones
behind the setup. They were here days
and days before. Please rise up on your
feet. Uh being led by your leader Milka.
These people were here from Monday last
this week setting up ensuring that
everything was okay and even after
tomorrow they'll be here to ensure that
everything is demolished. So you guys
may the Lord bless you. May the Lord
really really bless you. And at this
juncture, I want us to uh have our
visitors just rise up on your feet. If
this is your very first time, your first
time since Adam to join us here at Life
Church Liuru, please can you kindly rise
up on our feet. We appreciate and we
love our visitors and we want to love on
you. Thank you so much for coming and to
pay a visit to us. We are so delighted
that you would be with us here today and
we know that you know a house that is
not visited. So we thank you because you
are the ones that visit us. So at this
point I'd love to ask uh if you're a
visitor please kindly pick your
belongings, pick uh your bag uh and
follow these amazing hostesses as they
take you to a place we have specially
prepared for you. We have something
small even as we explain to you who
lifeurch is. So at this point you can uh
take up your belongings and follow these
amazing people to a place that they will
take you and I know we will have some
amazing time of fellowship. Can we
appreciate our visitors? Can we
appreciate our visitors?
Now in the afternoon we will have our
season finale for the DOXA conference
because DOCA is not ending and I know
Apostle Juma our father in the faith
Apostle Juma is going to be here and
that's why we also appreciate the group
of people that came to vend so if you're
here you want to look for something
quick to grab there are few vendors on
that side you will find too much sauce
they have amazing shawarmas we have
guard cakery we have Katrina Eights we
have honeymoon hotels we have kiki Vida,
we have cesi caterers and whimmer
caterers. All of these people uh have
food from pastry to fast food to actual
food to shawarma. You can grab something
as we go for lunch break. I know we're
going to be coming back right around
2:30. So please, we can take the 30
minutes to just dine and refresh our
bodies. If you don't want that, you can
stay here and begin to pray as you set
precedents for what's about to happen.
Amen. I also want to appreciate my
people. They texted me. They told me so
I want to appreciate my people at TED
and Aaria Consulting. I work with them
for many other things. At this point,
can we all rise up on our feet?
Yes. If you're a pastor and you're
visiting together with us, uh we have a
special place for you. Please, um I will
ask that the the hospitality team, the
protocol team will show you to your
place. So if you're a pastor, don't
leave. We have a special place for you.
I I can see some amazing pastors that we
have. So glad to see you guys. May God
bless you. I want to ask Apostle to give
us the words of the benediction as a
father and then we can take our break.
Hallelujah.
Amen. On Friday I met with a few friends
uh just for the project
and um in pledges and contribution
we managed to raise around 4.1 million
which will go
which will go towards the project. So
I'm so grateful th those are me and my
friends. So that's my contribution.
So,
amen.
You have my friends. We will see on
Sunday now how the sons are doing. If
the sons are doing better than my
friends, we will know on Sunday. Now,
turn, we are not finishing the service.
We we are transitioning. Turn to that
neighbor. Tell that neighbor, neighbor,
>> you're looking beautiful.
I tell that neighbor next Sunday even in
the afternoon I will not mind to
sickness to you. Tell that neighbor
neighbor I loved your cologne. I loved
your smile. I loved your presence.
And now share the words of the grace.
And now the grace of our Lord Jesus
Christ and the love of God and the
fellowship of the Holy Spirit be with us
now and forever more. Amen. Surely
goodness and mercy shall follow us and
money all the days of our lives and we
shall dwell in the house forever and
ever. Amen. Tell that neighbor the
afternoon meeting
is compulsory
for everybody.
So see you in the afternoon. God bless
you.
[Music]